[
  {
    "question": "What technological advancement in China allowed for the production of porcelain?",
    "a": "processing the clay to remove impurities",
    "b": "firing clay in extremely hot kilns",
    "c": "manufacturing new pigments for a white color",
    "d": "introducing new minerals to the clay",
    "e": "mixing clay with crushed glass",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which material would Romans typically use for the exterior facing of buildings?",
    "a": "marble",
    "b": "wood",
    "c": "limestone",
    "d": "bricks",
    "e": "concrete",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did Rome contribute to the historical use of concrete?",
    "a": "Romans spread its use throughout the empire.",
    "b": "Romans recreated older structures with it.",
    "c": "Romans invented it.",
    "d": "Romans traded concrete mixtures with other nations.",
    "e": "Romans established a single formula for it.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under which emperor did the Roman Empire reach its peak size to span three continents?",
    "a": "Hadrian",
    "b": "Augustus",
    "c": "Trajan",
    "d": "Titus",
    "e": "Septimus Severus",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What ingredient is unique to the ancient Roman mixture for concrete?",
    "a": "lime",
    "b": "water",
    "c": "mortar",
    "d": "stone pieces",
    "e": "pozzolana",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "After mixing the concrete, Romans",
    "a": "spread it across holes in stone structures",
    "b": "colored it with minerals",
    "c": "set it in water to harden",
    "d": "poured it over a brick base",
    "e": "shaped it in a wooden frame",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ashlar masonry creates structures out of",
    "a": "large stones",
    "b": "concrete",
    "c": "clay bricks",
    "d": "timber",
    "e": "stucco",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the beginning of the Roman Empire, Romans PRIMARILY used concrete to",
    "a": "seal foundations of structures",
    "b": "fill gaps in walls",
    "c": "construct curved arches and domes",
    "d": "make waterproof containers",
    "e": "lay stones for the road",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is concrete particularly useful in an area prone to earthquakes?",
    "a": "It can expand to fill new spaces.",
    "b": "It freezes the structure in place.",
    "c": "It allows layers to move with the quake.",
    "d": "It shifts the structure’s weight further into the ground.",
    "e": "It creates a stable foundation.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was NOT an advantage of working with concrete?",
    "a": "It could be made at the construction site.",
    "b": "It could create a variety of shapes.",
    "c": "It created strong bonds between materials.",
    "d": "It was less expensive than other materials.",
    "e": "It required little training to use.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why were concrete vaults brighter than stone vaults?",
    "a": "Concrete vaults could have windows throughout.",
    "b": "Concrete was thinner and let sunlight through.",
    "c": "Concrete vaults had wider openings on either end.",
    "d": "Concrete was more fire resistant and could have more lamps.",
    "e": "Concrete reflected more light.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the ancient Roman term for concrete?",
    "a": "opus caementicium",
    "b": "opus incertum",
    "c": "opus quadratum",
    "d": "opus spicatum",
    "e": "opus mixtum",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of structure did both Titus and Septimius Severus build as a monument of triumph?",
    "a": "roads",
    "b": "statues",
    "c": "columns",
    "d": "arches",
    "e": "temples",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of revetment?",
    "a": "to protect the interior structure from impacts",
    "b": "to stabilize a structure",
    "c": "to decorate a structure",
    "d": "to allow light into the structure",
    "e": "to prevent fires in the structure",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is NOT a way the Romans influenced the history of architecture?",
    "a": "They combined techniques to make new structures.",
    "b": "They popularized materials such as concrete.",
    "c": "They spread Roman political propaganda using architecture.",
    "d": "They invented new forms such as arches and domes.",
    "e": "They created durable structures that stood for a long time.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Pantheon was NOT intended to worship",
    "a": "Apollo",
    "b": "Saturn",
    "c": "Mars",
    "d": "Mercury",
    "e": "Jupiter",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "The word \"Pantheon\" is derived from the Greek term for",
    "a": "“all gods”",
    "b": "“temple of heaven”",
    "c": "“blessing of gods”",
    "d": "“palace of gods”",
    "e": "“heavenly tribute”",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Roman emperors ordered the construction of the Pantheon?",
    "a": "Augustus",
    "b": "Nero",
    "c": "Hadrian",
    "d": "Diocletian",
    "e": "Caesar",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the early seventh century, the Pantheon became a",
    "a": "church",
    "b": "museum",
    "c": "mosque",
    "d": "trade center",
    "e": "city hall",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "The structure of the Pantheon is the result of increased confidence in",
    "a": "concrete",
    "b": "columns",
    "c": "glass",
    "d": "marble",
    "e": "arches",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following materials went into the mixture for the bottommost foundation of the Pantheon?",
    "a": "basalt",
    "b": "brick",
    "c": "pumice",
    "d": "granite",
    "e": "tufa",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following materials fills the concrete at the very top of the Pantheon‘s dome?",
    "a": "granite",
    "b": "travertine stone",
    "c": "tufa",
    "d": "gravel",
    "e": "pumice",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following terms refers to the circular opening at the very top of the Pantheon’s dome?",
    "a": "oculus",
    "b": "vide",
    "c": "specula",
    "d": "coffer",
    "e": "visio",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In most ways, the front of the Pantheon is BEST described as",
    "a": "awe-inspiring",
    "b": "forbidding",
    "c": "unoriginal",
    "d": "towering",
    "e": "small",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Visitors to the Pantheon first walk through an entryway BEST described as",
    "a": "open and regal",
    "b": "narrow and colonnaded",
    "c": "empty and vast",
    "d": "crowded and dark",
    "e": "colorful and bright",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "For the Romans, the illuminated circle at the top of the dome represented the eye of",
    "a": "Jupiter",
    "b": "Neptune",
    "c": "Minerva",
    "d": "Juno",
    "e": "Mars",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of the following areas of the Pantheon are the seven large niches?",
    "a": "rotunda",
    "b": "portico",
    "c": "dome",
    "d": "doorway",
    "e": "collonade",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Each of the seven niches in the Pantheon once represented a different",
    "a": "emperor",
    "b": "deity",
    "c": "continent",
    "d": "ideal",
    "e": "military leader",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following shapes decorates the floor of the Pantheon?",
    "a": "circles",
    "b": "stars",
    "c": "rectangles",
    "d": "rhombuses",
    "e": "triangles",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following types of columns is used to support the triangular and rounded pediments in the Pantheon?",
    "a": "Tuscan",
    "b": "Composite",
    "c": "Ionic",
    "d": "Doric",
    "e": "Corinthian",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  }
]

